<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<document xmlns="http://di.tamu.edu/DRI/1.0/" xmlns:i18n="http://apache.org/cocoon/i18n/2.1" version="1.1">
<body>
<div id="file.news.div.news" n="news" rend="primary">
<p><head>Explore. Interact. Understand.</head></p>
<p><hi rend="bold">VSim</hi> is a simple-to-use interface for exploring computer models of historic sites and environments. Designed to support both teacher-centered presentations and student-centered assignments, this NEH-funded software is perfect for classroom use.</p>
<p>The VSim interface is flexible, and can fit into any classroom. <xref target="/xmlui/pages/download">Click here to download the software.</xref></p>
<p>Once you’ve download the VSim software, <a href="{$app_path}/projects">browse the archive</a> to download models, narratives, and embedded resources. The <hi rend="bold">VSim Repository and Archive</hi> preserves academically generated models for use in both formal and informal educational settings. Scholars across the country have constructed these models to exacting standards, so they are ideal teaching and learning resources.</p>
<p><hi rend="bold">Interested in using VSim in your classroom?</hi></p>
<p>Before getting started, <xref target="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TUz086WMGNU">watch this tutorial</xref> and review the <xref target="https://idre.ucla.edu/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/vsim-v1-userguide-june2013.pdf?x83242">VSim Software user guide</xref>. <xref target="/xmlui/pages/tour">A quick tour can be found here.</xref></p>
<p><hi rend="bold">Interested in contributing a model?</hi></p>
<p>Before getting started, review the VSim Archive user guide (coming soon). To contribute models to the VSim Repository and Archive, create a user account and request an upgrade to content creator status. <xref target="/xmlui/pages/add">Click here to get started.</xref></p>
<p>For more detailed information about the VSim software and repository, <xref target="/xmlui/pages/about">visit our About page.</xref></p>
</div>
</body>
<options/>
<meta>
<userMeta/>
<pageMeta/>
<repositoryMeta/>
</meta>
</document>
