<document xmlns="http://di.tamu.edu/DRI/1.0/" xmlns:i18n="http://apache.org/cocoon/i18n/2.1" version="1.1">

<body>
<div id="file.add.div.add" n="news" rend="primary">

<head>Submitting Content to the VSim Repository and Archive</head>

<hi rend="bold">Submitting to the VSim Repository and Archive is easy.</hi>

<p>The long-term vision of the project is to build a thriving community of scholars and educators creating and sharing 3D content. To contribute to the repository and archive, users can register for a free account under the following types:</p>

<hi rend="bold">User Types</hi>
<p>
    <hi rend="italic">Unregistered User:</hi> Anyone can download VSim and content from the 
    archive without registering as a user.
</p>

<p>
    <hi rend="italic">General User:</hi> Registered General Users can upload VSim narratives, embedded resource files, and archival content to the community collections of the different 3D projects through the “Submissions” link on the main project page. If you’ve created a VSim narrative or a lesson plan for a particular project, please share!
</p>

<p>
    <hi rend="italic">Content Contributor/Creator:</hi> General users must request permission to upgrade their account to ‘Content Creator’ so that they can submit their own models and projects to the VSim Repository and Archive. Access is granted on a case-by-case basis by the Digital Library Program and the Institute for Digital Research and Education. Submission requests for models and projects will be vetted for their academic rigor and educational contribution to the community. <hi rend="bold">To request a free upgraded account, users should e-mail vsim@library.ucla.edu with your full name, institutional affiliation, a short description of the project and/or model (approximately 800 words), and a bibliography of resources that informed the construction of the model and guided the project.</hi> Requests may take up to a week to approve. 
</p>

<hi rend="bold">For Registered General Users -- How to contribute content to a project’s Submissions collection</hi>
<p>
    1. Register to become a General User.
</p>
<p>
    Any registered user can submit content to a project’s Submissions collection. If you have not registered for a free account, (<xref target="/xmlui/register">click here</xref>).
</p>
<p>
    2. Go to a Project page.
</p>
<p>
    3. Click on "Submissions" under "Related Files."
</p>
<p>
    4. Click "Submit a new item to this collection."
</p>
<p>
    Complete the short item form, which asks for some basic information about the resource, such as creator, date, and title. Upload your file. To see what what types of files are accepted, please see the (<xref target="/xmlui/pages/faq">FAQs</xref>).
</p>

<hi rend="bold">For Content Creators -- How to Submit a Project</hi>
<p>
    1. Register and become a Content Creator.
</p>
<p>
    Content Creators can submit a model to the archive. If you have not registered for a free account, (<xref target="/xmlui/register">click here</xref>), and then request to become a Content Creator by following the instructions found under the "Content Creator" in the "User Type" section above.
</p>
<p>
    2. Create a project page for your model and archival materials.
</p>
<p>
    The submission process involves completion of the project metadata form, and uploading a ‘hero’ image to be used as the project thumbnail. Once your project is approved, you can begin to add models and related content to your project archive.
</p>
<p>
    3. Populate your project archive.
</p>
<p>
   From your project page, submit new items to your Vsim Files, Archives, or Submissions. Follow instructions in the VSim Repository and Archive user guide. To see what what types of files are accepted, please see the (<xref target="/xmlui/pages/faq">FAQs</xref>).
</p>    
<p>
   Now click on the "Submit Project" button to get started.
</p>

</div>

</body>

<meta>
<pageMeta>
<metadata element="title">Submit Works to VSim</metadata>
<trail target="../">VSim Home</trail>
<trail target="#">Submit Works to VSim</trail>
</pageMeta>
</meta>

</document>
