<document xmlns="http://di.tamu.edu/DRI/1.0/" xmlns:i18n="http://apache.org/cocoon/i18n/2.1"
    version="1.1">

    <body>
        <div id="file.about.div.download" n="about" rend="primary">
            <head>VSim Downloads</head>

            <hi rend="bold">The NEH-funded VSim Prototype Version 1</hi>

            <p>VSim was designed so that it could be used as a platform to peer review, publish, and broadly disseminate academically generated 3D content. The NEH-funded VSim prototype was first released in 2013. The most recent is VSim 1.2.1 for Windows. This version can also be used on a dual-boot Mac or through Windows emulating software (e.g., Parallels). The prototype was built as a proof-of-concept to allow the VSim team to assess the educational possibilities of three-dimensional content and the software's functionality. Development is underway on an enhanced version of the software, which will be available on this page as soon as it is fully tested.</p>
            

            <list>
            <item><xref target="https://idre.ucla.edu/?wpdmdl=5349">Click to download VSim (v 1.2.1)</xref> (20MB).
            (This version is Windows-compatible and opens .dae, .flt., .ive, and .vsim model files)</item>
            </list>
            
            <hi rend="bold">User guides, tutorials, and presentations</hi>

            <list>
              <item><xref target="https://idre.ucla.edu/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/vsim-v1-userguide-june2013.pdf?x83242">Users’ guide</xref> (last updated June 13, 2013).</item>
              <item><xref target="https://idre.ucla.edu/sites/default/files/vsim-v1-graphicguide-july2013.pdf?x83242">Short graphic guide</xref> (last updated July 9, 2013).</item>
              <item>A brief introduction to the main features of VSim posted on <xref target="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MYYtDTucKL8">YouTube</xref>.</item>
              <item><xref target="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TUz086WMGNU">VSim Tutorial on YouTube</xref> captured at the Humanities Heritage NEH
              Summer Institute (NEH Advanced Topics in the Digital Humanites
                    Summer Institute, The Center for Digital Initiatives, Arkansas
                    State University)</item>
            </list>

            <hi rend="bold">Directions for installing the VSim prototype on Windows systems</hi>

            <list rend="numeric" type="ordered">
            <item>Create a VSim folder on your hard drive</item>
            <item>Right click on the links and ‘save link as ...’ the software, sample model, and other files as desired</item>
            <item>Unzip the VSim .zip file (typically a right click, choose WinZip from the menu, and ‘extract to here’)</item>
            <item>Navigate into the release folder and double click the VSim.exe file to launch the software</item>
            <item>To begin using VSim, click File -> Open Model and browse for your downloaded 3D content</item>
            <item>Read the user guide for help loading models and creating narratives of your own!</item>
          </list>
            
               </div>
    </body>


    <meta>
        <pageMeta>
            <metadata element="title">VSim Downloads</metadata>
            <trail target="../">VSim Home</trail>
            <trail target="#">VSim Downloads</trail>
        </pageMeta>
    </meta>

</document>
